Finding Aid for Dan L. DeGrow Papers, 1981-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dan L. DeGrow Papers 1981-2002
DeGrow, Dan L.
4 linear ft.
0631 Aa 2
The Daniel L. DeGrow collection documents his activities as Republican member of the Michigan legislature from 1981 to 2002. The collection includes hardbound volumes of press releases issued by DeGrow and colleagues, columns written by DeGrow for various publications, and press clips from publications across the state.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dan L. DeGrow (donor no. 9700 ) and came to the library on February 21, 2006.
The collection is open to research.
Dan L. DeGrow was born June 28, 1953 in Ann Arbor Michigan. He attended Port Huron Northern High School and St. Clair Community College before graduating Phi Beta Kappa from Michigan State University in 1975. He received a J.D. from Wayne State University in 1978 and practiced law for several years.
DeGrow was elected to the Michigan House of Representatives in 1980 and was elected as State Senator for the 27th Senate District in 1982. He represented the 27th district from 1983 to 2002. From 1995 to 1998 DeGrow served as the Senate Majority floor leader and from 1999 to 2002 he was the Senate Majority leader.
DeGrow was an outspoken proponent of improving Michigan's public schools and after leaving the legislature he became superintendent of the St. Clair County Intermediate School District.
Records in this collection document Dan DeGrow's tenure in the Michigan legislature, spanning from 1981 to 2002. The collection consists of four series of hardbound volumes: Press Releases, Columns, Press Clips, and Miscellaneous.
Subjects:
DeGrow, Dan L.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Michigan--Politics and government--1991-2000.; Michigan--Politics and government--2001-2010.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Press Releases
  The Press Releases series (0.5 ft) spans from 1985 to 2002. It includes official press releases relating to DeGrow's activities in the legislature. These releases include those from DeGrow's office, the Michigan Republican party, and fellow politicians.
  - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 1)
- Columns
  The Columns series 0(.5 ft) spans from 1991 to 2000. This series contains articles written by DeGrow for publications such as the Sanilac County News and the Yale Expositor, among others. They discuss the activities of the Michigan legislature, proposed legislation, and current events. The columns address issues of importance on both a state and national level including telecommunications, tobacco, transportation, natural resources and the environment.
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 1)
- Press Clips
  The Press Clips series (3 ft.) makes up the majority of the collection and spans from 1981 to 2002. This series includes articles from newspapers around the state of Michigan that discuss various legislative activities in which DeGrow was involved.
  - 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - 1987 (Box 2)
  - 1988 (Box 2)
  - 1991 (Box 2)
  - 1992 (Box 2)
  - 1993 (Box 3)
  - 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - 1997 (Box 3)
  - 1998 (Box 3)
  - 1999, 3 volumes (Box 3)
  - 2000 (Box 4)
  - 2001, 3 volumes (Box 4)
  - 2002, 2 volumes (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  Miscellaneous is a small series consisting of some campaign materials, a few snapshots of DeGrow at public functions, and a sampling of some of the thank you letters he received while serving in the legislature.
  - Campaign literature, published material (Box 4)
  - Photographs of DeGrow with political figures and at a farmers' market (Box 4)
  - Thank you letters, 1991-2002 (Box 4)